Guide to the Rice University Faculty offprints collection, 1897-2005 UA 006
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Faculty offprints collection
1897-2005
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Unknown
UA 006
7.5 Linear Feet (14 boxes and 1 carton)
Faculty offprints, reproductions of individual articles published in scholarly journals, written by Rice University professors, with publication dates ranging from 1897 to 2005.
Biographical Note
This collection contains offprints dating between 1897 and 2005, written by Rice University faculty members. 'Offprints' are reproductions of individual articles that were published in a scholarly journal. Thus, the material contained in this collection provides a sample of the writing and publication activity of many Rice University professors throughout the twentieth century.
Scope and Contents
Faculty offprints, reproductions of individual articles published in scholarly journals, written by Rice University professors, with publication dates ranging from 1897 to 2005. The earliest materials were written by Prof. H.A. Wilson, of the Physics department. The bulk of the materials are from 1910-1980.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
Material transferred to Woodson Research Center beginning in 1968.
Index Terms
Subjects
Faculty; Universities and colleges
Document Types
offprints
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Series I: Faculty A-W, 1897-1990, 118929
  - Aldrich, V. C., 1932-1941; 112326 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bonner, T. W., 1932-1947; 112340 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Altenburg, E., 1916-1955; 112327 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Altamira, Rafael, 1916; 112328 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, M. D., 1926-1937; 112329 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arvin, N. C., 1918-1924; 112331 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Banka, H. E., 1929-1941; 112332 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Beckenbach, E. F., 1929-1945; 112333 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Belaunde, V. A., 1923; 112334 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bennett, W. E., 1936-1947; 112335 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Binney, J. H., 1935; 112336 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Arrowood, C. F., 1924-1935; 112330 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bishop, W. W., 1945; 112337 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Blayney, L., 1910-1963; 112338 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Blumenthal, L. M., 1926-1937; 112339 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Boucher, P. E., 1925; 112341 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bourgeois, A., 1938-1947; 112342 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bray. H. E., 1919-1929; 112343 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bridger, G. L., 1935-1938; 112344 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Broker, Hugo, 1930; 112345 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brunk, H. D., 1945; 112346 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bryan, A. B., 1921-1929; 112347 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Caldwell, R. G., 1915-1932; 112348 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Camden, C., 1932-1949; 112349 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Carpenter, W., 1917; 112350 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Chillman, J. H., 1924-1941; 112352 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Conklin, E. G., 1930-1938; 112353 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Copeland, A. H., 1927-1941; 112354 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Craig, H. Jr., 1949-1960; 112355 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Craig, W. M., 1923; 112356 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Crawford, B. V., 1919-1922; 112357 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cunningham, G., 1928; 112358 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Daniel, P. J., 1913-1919; 112359 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Davies, Joseph, 112360 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Davis, S. H., 1957; 112361 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Deevey, E. S., 1940-1945; 112362 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Diamant, N. S., 1915-1918; 112363 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Dix, C. H., 1930; 112364 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Durham, E. J, 1930; 112365 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Durst, L. K., 1963; 112366 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Echols, W. H., 1912; 112367 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Escher, E., n.d.; 112368 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ettlinger, M. G., 1946-1962; 112369 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Evans, G. C. (1), 1911-1937; 112370 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Evans, G. C. (2), 1910-1939; 112371 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Eversole, W. J., 1939-1944; 112372 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Falconer, R., 1940; 112373 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ford, L. R., 1925-1935; 112374 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Franklin, J. L., 1973-1975; 112375 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Fulton, J. F., 1940-1942; 112376 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Garrison, A. D., 1921-1939; 112377 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Gergen, J. J., 1930; 112378 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Geyer, D. L., 1914-1917; 112379 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Gilbert, A. H., 1911-1922; 112380 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Graustein, W. C., 1913-1924; 112381 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Guerard, Albert, 1908-1959; 112382 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hall, G. S., 1915; 112383 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hall, R. P., 1923-1928; 112384 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Harris, S., 1934; 112385 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Harwood, P. D., 1932; 112386 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Heaps, C., 1911-1941; 112387 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hendren, J. W., 1936-1938; 112388 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Hermance, G., 1934-1937; 112389 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Hitchens, K., 1964-1965; 112390 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Howell, L. B., 1920-1923; 112391 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hudspeth, E., 1940; 112392 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Hurley, F. H., 1934-1940; 112393 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Huxley, J., 1914-1958; 112394 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Johnson, C. R., 1930; 112395 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Kilpatrick, J. E., 1947 and n.d.; 112396 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Kirner, W. R., 1928-1930; 112397 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Kolenda, K., 1958-1990; 112398 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Krzyzaniak, M., 1968-1975; 112399 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Lear, F. S., 1929-1963; 112431 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Leighton, W., 1938-1966; 112432 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Le Vavasseur, 1912; 112433 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Lewis, E. S., 1954-1962; 112434 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Little, R. N., 1941; 112435 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Locher, G. L., 1932; 112436 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Lyle, W. T., 1920-1921; 112437 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Lynch, J. A., 1927-1942; 112438 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - MacLane, G. R., 112439 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - MacMahon, A., 1925-1926; 112440 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Mallison, A. G., 1920; 112441 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mandelbrojt, S., 1925-1944; 112442 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Mandeville, C. E., 1942-1948; 112443 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Maxwell, B., 1922; 112444 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Margrave, J. L., 1974-1975; 112445 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - McCann, S. G., 1917; 112446 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Menger, K., 1941; 112447 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Meyer, H., 1932-1942; 112448 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Michal, A. D., 1925-1941; 112450 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Miles, E. R. C., 1929; 112451 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Miller, H., 1910-1912; 112452 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Miller, J. M., 112454 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Milligan, W. O., 1931-1956; 112455 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Moraud, M., 1928-1968; 112458 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Moreland, F. B., 112459 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Morris, C. W., 1927-1939; 112460 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Mott-Smith, L. M., 1928-1934; 112461 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Muller, H., 1914; 112462 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Murnaghan, F. D., 1917; 112463 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Myers, C. S., 1908; 112464 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nicholas, H. O., 1929-1951; 112465 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nock, S. A., 1929; 112468 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Norbeck, E., 112469 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - O'Brien, J., 1965; 112471 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Pattie, F. A. Jr., 1930-1941; 112472 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Phillips, G. C., n.d.; 112473 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Pipes, L. A., 1937; 112474 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Porter, E. E., 1927; 112475 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Resnikoff, H. L., 1970-1971; 112476 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Rhodes, S. A., 1927; 112477 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Richards, H. T., 1941-1947; 112478 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Richter, G. H., 1933-1940; 112479 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ricker, N., 1916-1953; 112480 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Roos, C. F., 1925-1929; 112481 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Rossini, F. D., 1947; 112482 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Scott, A. F., 1931-1937; 112483 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Scott, H. A., 1930-1936; 112484 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Scott, W. T., 1939; 112485 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Sherrick, J. L., n.d.; 112486 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Smith, J. T., 1949; 112487 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Squire, C. F., 1947; 112488 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Starnes, D. T., 1922-1944; 112489 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Stewart, M. A., 1929-1934; 112490 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Struthers, L. B., 1919; 112491 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Swabey, W. C., 1919-1920; 112492 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Thom, W. T. Jr., 1934 & n.d.; 112493 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Tsanoff, R. A., 1910-1942; 112496 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Ulrich, F. E., 1939-1942; 112498 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Warburton, C. A., 1927-1938; 112499 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ward, C. F., 1911; 112500 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Watt, B. E., 1940-1941; 112501 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Watt, J. S., 1925; 112502 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Weber, R., 1918; 112503 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Wendt, G. L., 1916; 112504 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - White, A. F., 1920-1923; 112506 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Williamson, W. J., 1933; 112507 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Wilson, H. A., 1897-1915; 112510 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Wilson, H. A. (Royal Society Proceedings), 1907-1952; 112511 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Wilson, H. A., 1898-1954; 112512 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Wischmeyer, C., 1940; 112513 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Woodbridge, B. M., 1916-1937; 112514 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Woodbridge, B. M., 1911-1945; 112515 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Wright, Q., 1966; 112516 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Series II: Rice President Kenneth S. Pitzer, 1935-1968, 118930
  - Pitzer, Kenneth Sanborn. Publications Listing., 1968; 112555 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 3-4., 1935-1936; 112558 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 5-12., 1937; 112560 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 13-18., 1938; 112563 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 19-21., 1939; 112564 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 22-28., 1940; 112567 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 29-38., 1941-1942; 112569 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 39-42., 1943-1944; 112570 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 43-50., 1945; 112571 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 51-62., 1945-1946.; 112572 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 64-72., 1947; 112575 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 73-77., 1948; 112576 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 78-88., 1949; 112577 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 89-93., 1950-1951; 112578 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 94-104., 1952-1953; 112579 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 105-112., 1954-1955; 112580 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 113-129., 1956-1957; 112581 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 130-141., 1958; 112582 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 142-150., 1959; 112583 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 151-170., 1960-1962; 112584 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 172-178., 1963-1964; 112585 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Pitzer, K. S. Publications 179-187., 1965-1968; 112586 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Series III: Addendum, Faculty A -W, 1951-1988, 118931
  - Adams, J. A. S., 1954; 112608 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Adams, M., 1975; 112609 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Altenburg, L., 1952; 112610 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Asimow, R., n.d.; 112611 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bird, G. R., 1954; 112612 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Black, H. C., 1954; 112613 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Brotzen, F. R., 1955; 112614 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Chapman, A. J., 1954; 112615 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Dowden, W. S., 1955; 112616 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Kraus, A., 1954; 112617 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Millikan, R. A., 1954; 112618 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Nielson, N. C., 1955; 112619 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Rorschach, H. E., 1951; 112620 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Talmage, R. V., 1956; 112621 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Thomas, J. D., 1954; 112622 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Turner, R. B., 1954-1956; 112626 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Waser, J., 1953-1955; 112630 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1962-1969; 112587 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1970-1975; 112598 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1976; 112641 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1977; 112600 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1978-1979; 112642 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1980; 112602 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1981; 112603 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1982-1984; 112604 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1987; 112605 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1988 (1); 112606 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Schroepfer, G. J., Jr., 1988 (2); 112607 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Stebbings, R. F., 112649 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Stebbings, R. F., 1984-1987; 112644 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Stebbings, R. F., 1988-1989; 112645 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Stebbings, R. F., 1990-1994; 112646 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Stebbings, R. F., 1996-1998; 112647 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Stebbings, R. F., 2003-2005; 112648 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Addendum, Faculty Offprints, 1980-2004, 149173
  - Glantz, Raymon M., 1988-2004; 149174 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Glantz, Raymon M., 1980-1988; 149175 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Gomer, R. H., 1994-1999; 149176 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Gomer, R. H., 1981-1995; 149177 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Rudolph, Frederich B., 1980-1996; 149178 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Schroepfer, G. J. Jr., 1995-1999; 149179 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Schroepfer, G. J. Jr., 1992-1994; 149180 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Schroepfer, G. J. Jr., 1989-1992; 149181 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Schroepfer, G. J. Jr., 1980-1989; 149182 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Walters, G.K. (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
  - Curl, Robert, 1950s (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Curl, Robert, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Curl, Robert, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Curl, Robert, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Curl, Robert, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Curl, Robert, 2000s (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1950s (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1960-1965 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1966-1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1970-1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1976-1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1980-1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1990-1995 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Hellums, J.D., 1996-1999 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Hellums, J.D., 2000s (Box 14, Folder 10)